Contact

morellojonathan@yahoo.com

www.linkedin.com/in/jonathan-morello-msn-rn-ccm-11b240112 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Proficency in Microsoft Windows and Mac Operating Systems Microsoft Office Citrix

Certifications

Registered Nurse License, New Hampshire

Certified Case Manager (CCM)

Registered Nurse License, Florida

Registered Nurse License, Massachusetts

IHI Basic

Honors-Awards

Excellence in use of Critical Thinking in a Clinical Setting

Sigma Theta Tau International Honor Society - Beta Mu Chapter

Presentation and Panelist at the Type 1 Diabetes (T1D) Exchange - Glu Community Event - Managed Care Insurance and Diabetes

Jonathan Morello, MSN, RN, CCM

Vice President, Medical Management at Centene Corporation Greater Boston Area

Summary

Dynamic nursing professional with demonstrated transformational leadership skills, including hiring, recruiting, and motivating talented individuals, assisting with individual development and mentorship of front-line, and supervisory/managerial level staff, cultivating and maintaining professional relationships with executive leadership, physicians, front-line staff, state/community agencies. Extensive experience in a variety of nursing specialties including Managed Care, Case Management, Utilization Management, Medicare Quality Improvement Organizations (QIO), Neurosurgical Critical Care, Medical/Surgical, and Geriatrics.

Experience

Centene Corporation 6 years 8 months

Vice President, Medical Management June 2020 - Present (2 months)

Senior Director, Utilization Management April 2016 - June 2020 (4 years 3 months)

Duties: Direct responsibility and accountability for all Utilization Management activities and operations, including inpatient and outpatient Prior Authorization, and Concurrent Review for Medicaid, Medicaid Expansion and Commercial products. Management and oversight of the Manager of Utilization Management, Clinical Nurse Liaison, and Senior Trainer for Utilization Management. Ensuring turnaround time frames are met according to state contract and National Committee for Quality Assurance (NCQA) standards.

Projects: Co-Chair of the Provider Satisfaction committee, Co-Chair of the Employee Engagement and Employee Activities Committee, Member of the Transitions of Care (TOC) committee, which has an emphasis and focus on

discharge planning and care transitions from the inpatient setting to the next level of care.

Senior Manager, Case Management December 2013 - April 2016 (2 years 5 months)

Duties: Management and oversight of two Case Management departments supporting multiple products and lines of business at different site locations including two nursing supervisors and 30 clinical and non-clinical front-line staff, instituting department and clinical program metrics, representing the health plan during internal and external stakeholder meetings and presentations both in person, via telephone, and WebEx/Webinar, providing key deliverables

resulting in successful outcomes during corporate and vendor internal audits, external quality

review (EQRO) audits, state readiness reviews and operational reviews for the Department of

Health and Human Services, providing subject matter expertise (SME) during new business

readiness for upcoming product launch. Required business travel to corporate headquarters in St.

Louis, Missouri and health plan location in Austin, Texas.

Projects:

Co-Chair of both the Employee Activities Committee and Employee Engagement

Committee, training, implementation, and development of the Integrated Care Management

(ICM) program blending physical health and behavioral health clinicians, clinical consultation

and oversight, assisting with preparation and submission for two National Committee for Quality Assurance (NCQA) accreditation reviews. Working with community partners on health promotion and risk reduction activities, including promoting and supporting a children's exercise program.

FMQAI

Manager, Case Review

September 2010 - November 2013 (3 years 3 months)

Duties: Managing daily workflow of 20 nurse Case Managers, responsible for the delegation and oversight of 20 non-clinical staff including medical records, helpline team, and administrative staff, supporting multiple lines of business including Florida, California, Georgia, Arizona, North Dakota, South Dakota, Washington, and Idaho, leadership designee for the Disaster Response Team (DRT) with oversight of the virtual team for business continuity. Required business travel to Las Vegas, Nevada.

Projects: Designated Medicare Quality Improvement Organization (QIO) Brand Ambassador, working with senior leadership in the development of the Electronic Case Review Tool (ECRT), and training/implementation of the Case Review Management Information System (CRMIS) application, Recovery Audit Contract (RAC) review of inpatient hospitalizations for utilization.

WellCare Health Plans
Registered Nurse Case Manager
January 2010 - September 2010 (9 months)

Duties: Assisting members and providers with coordination of care, supporting multiple products and lines of business for members in managed Medicare and Medicaid health plan markets including Florida, Texas, Ohio, and Indiana while ensuring accurate, crisp, and appropriate documentation within the Enterprise Medical Management Automation (EMMA) system.

Projects: Participation in the cultural diversity committee, and step action/ process improvement committee.

Amerigroup
Registered Nurse Care Coordinator
August 2008 - January 2010 (1 year 6 months)

Duties: Assisting members and providers in obtaining prior authorization for health care services, supporting multiple products and lines of business, specifically members in managed Medicaid health plan markets across Florida, Virginia, Georgia, New York, Texas, Nevada, Tennessee, South Carolina, and Maryland while ensuring accurate, crisp, and appropriate documentation within the FACETS system.

Projects: Subject Matter Expert (SME) for clinical services team, interim Team Leader serving as a liaison between review staff and medical directors for complex review, collaborating on the Integrated Customer Solutions (ICS) project as a clinical subject matter expert (SME) on site in Tampa, Florida and required business travel to corporate headquarters in Virginia Beach, Virginia.

Education

LSU Shreveport

Master of Business Administration - MBA, Currently attending AACSB accredited MBA program - Anticipated graduation Spring/Summer 2021. · (2020 - 2021)

The University of Arizona College of Nursing

Master of Science, Nursing - Clinical Systems Leadership · (2015 - 2016)

St. Petersburg College

Bachelor of Science (B.S.), Nursing · (2006 - 2008)

St. Petersburg College

Associate of Science (A.S.), Registered Nursing/Registered Nurse · (2002 - 2006)

Galen School of Nursing-Tampa Bay

Diploma, Licensed Practical/Vocational Nurse Training · (2003 - 2004)